<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="complete">World Wide Diplomatic Archives Index: Australia</title>
                <title type="short">Australia</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Legislation">
                <head>Legislation</head>
                <p>The public may apply for access to any Commonwealth records that are more than 30
                    years old. If a member of the public requires access to a Commonwealth record
                    more than 30 years old that is not in a National Archives repository, the
                    Archives, in cooperation with the Australian Government agency with custody of
                    the record, will facilitate the provision of access to that record. Under the
                    Freedom of Information Act, public researchers may apply for special access to
                    records that are younger than 30 years old on the basis that they are preparing
                    a major work of national significance for publication.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Location">
                <head>Location</head>
                <p>The National Archives has offices in Canberra, Darwin and the State Capitals.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Procedures">
                <head> Procedures</head>
                <p> Researchers may visit any of the locations of the National Archives, but they
                    are advised to write to the Archives staff ahead of time to ensure a timely
                    start to their inquiries. E-mail addresses and phone numbers are found on the
                    website.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Website">
                <head>Website</head>
                <p>
                    <ref target="http://www.naa.gov.au">National Archives</ref>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Publications">
                <head>Published Documents</head>
                <p>The Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade also has a Historical Documents
                    Project Section which produces the series, Documents on Australian Foreign
                    Policy.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>