<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="complete">World Wide Diplomatic Archives Index: Chile</title>
                <title type="short">Chile</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Legislation">
                <head>Legislation</head>
                <p>Access to diplomatic archives is governed by the Administrative Directive for
                    Documentation of 1983. Unclassified documents are available for public
                    consultation 20 years after origination. Classified documents (Confidential and
                    Secret) are declassified 30 years after origination. Documents that are
                    considered of permanent interest of the Foreign Ministry are retained and not
                    declassified. Chile passed a freedom of information law in the summer of
                    2008.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Location">
                <head>Location</head>
                <p>Archive of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs: Bandera 52 entrepiso (between
                    Plaza/Ground Floor level and 1st Floor), Santiago, Chile. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Procedures">
                <head> Procedures</head>
                <p> The Archive of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs houses the greater part of the
                    Chilean Government’s diplomatic records and treaties, as well as diplomatic
                    lists (Chilean ambassadors and consuls overseas; foreign ambassadors and consuls
                    in Chile), a photographic collection, a map/credentials/other materials
                    collection, and several collections of the papers of former Chilean diplomats.
                    Researchers (Chilean and foreign) must bring a letter from their supporting
                    institution (academic or professional) or their advising professor stating the
                    reason, subject, and time period of their research. For foreign researchers, a
                    letter from their embassy or consulate stating the same information will be
                    accepted. Researchers are also asked to provide the Archive with a copy of their
                    finished work. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Website">
                <head>Website</head>
                <p>
                    <ref
                        target="http://www.minrel.gov.cl/prontus_minrel/site/edic/base/port/home.php"
                        >Archive of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs</ref>
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
