<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="complete">World Wide Diplomatic Archives Index: China</title>
                <title type="short">China</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Legislation">
                <head>Legislation</head>
                <p>According to legislation passed in 1980, foreign relations documents (along with
                    other historical materials) for all of Chinese history up to 1949 were to be
                    made available to the public and researchers. According to an Archive Law of
                    1987, diplomatic and other archives are to become open after 30 years.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Location">
                <head>Location</head>
                <p>Post-1949: Foreign Ministry Archives, No. 2, Chaoyangmen Nandajie, Chaoyang
                    District, Beijing, 100701</p>
                <p>1912-1949: Second Historical Archives, 309 East Zhongshan Road, Nanjing,
                    210016</p>
                <p>Pre-1912: First Historical Archives, National Palace Museum, Xihuamennei,
                    Beijing, 100031 </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Procedures">
                <head>Procedures</head>
                <p>These vary from archive to archive, but generally speaking no prior contact with
                    the archives is needed, and an application can be filled out upon arrival. A
                    letter from your home institution is usually sufficient to gain access to the
                    First and Second Historical Archives, but a letter from a Chinese institution is
                    required for access to the Foreign Ministry Archives (and would help at the
                    others as well). At least one form of official identification is also required.
                    There are finding aids, and there is no blanket fee to access the collection.
                    However, at the Foreign Ministry Archives, where everything that can be viewed
                    has been digitized, there is a cost to view each page. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Website">
                <head>Website</head>
                <p>
                    <ref target="http://dag.fmprc.gov.cn/chn/">Foreign Ministry Archives</ref>
                    (Chinese language) </p>
                <p>
                    <ref target="http://www.shac.net.cn/english/">Second Historical Archives</ref>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <ref target="http://www.lsdag.com/">First Historical Archives</ref> (Chinese
                    language) </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Publications">
                <head>Published Documents</head>
                <p>A collection of documents relating to China’s relations with Western nations
                    prior to 1911 was published in the 1930s, under the title of Collection of
                    Documents on the Management of Foreign Matters (Chouban yiwu shimo), and
                    beginning in the 1950s the PRC Government began publishing collections of
                    documents relating to particular episodes in its foreign relations. Since 1981,
                    the First and Second Historical Archives have issued several journals that
                    publish small collections of documents along with scholarly essays, and the
                    Chinese Academy of Social Sciences has done the same.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
