<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="complete">World Wide Diplomatic Archives Index: Czech Republic</title>
                <title type="short">Czech Republic</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Legislation">
                <head>Legislation</head>
                <p>The Archives of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Czech Republic are
                    administered by the Ministry of Interior. Material older than 30 years is open
                    to researchers. A member of the public may view documents not older than 30
                    years only with the permission of the director of the specific archive. All
                    archive materials remain classified if they could threaten the security of the
                    state or of the public, or interests of people still living that are protected
                    by law. Research in the Archives of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs is permitted
                    based on a prior written request that states the subject and purpose of the
                    research.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Location">
                <head>Location</head>
                <p> Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Czech Republic Administration and Information
                    Processing Department, Loretánské nám. č. 5, 118 00 Praha 1 </p>
                <p> The main research room and library are located in a new Archives' site in Prague
                    4 - Chodovec. It is accessible by public transportation. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Procedures">
                <head> Procedures</head>
                <p>Researchers should send a written request detailing which documents they would
                    like to see. Identification is required to access the reading rooms.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Website">
                <head>Website</head>
                <p>
                    <ref target="http://www.nacr.cz/eindex.htm">National Archives</ref>
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>