<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="complete">World Wide Diplomatic Archives Index: Taiwan</title>
                <title type="short">Taiwan</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Legislation">
                <head>Legislation</head>
                <p>The Archives Act of 1999 stipulates that government documents shall be made
                    available at the National Archives after 30 years, unless they fall under one of
                    the exceptions to the rule. This is decided by the creating agency. This law can
                    also be applied to documents held at several other locations.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Location">
                <head>Location</head>
                <p> There are two main locations in Taiwan that house documents from the Foreign
                    Ministry and other foreign relations documents: </p>
                <p> National Archives: No. 10, Lane 59, Yitong St., Zhongshan District, Taipei City
                    10486, Taiwan. Holdings: Documents on foreign relations in collections from the
                    National Assembly and other government bureaus. </p>
                <p>Academia Historica: 406 Beiyi Road Section 2, Xindian, Taipei County, Taiwan.
                    Holdings: Foreign Ministry Archives, Chiang Kai-shek Papers, and other documents
                    on foreign relations.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Procedures">
                <head> Procedures</head>
                <p>Researchers must fill out an application for access to the National Archives,
                    which can be found on the Archives website. For access to the Academia
                    Historica, you need to register at the front gate; bring a passport and a letter
                    of introduction from your home institution or one in Taiwan.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Website">
                <head>Website</head>
                <p>
                    <ref target="http://www.archives.gov.tw/english/">National Archives</ref>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <ref target="http://www.drnh.gov.tw/www/index.aspx">Academia Historica</ref>
                    (Chinese site) </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Publications">
                <head>Published Documents</head>
                <p>Both of these archives have published numerous volumes of foreign relations
                    documents. For their catalogs, see <ref
                        target="http://www.archives.gov.tw/english/Book/Public.aspx?cnid=398"/> and
                        <ref target="http://book.drnh.gov.tw/"/>.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
