<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="complete">World Wide Diplomatic Archives Index: The United States of
                    America</title>
                <title type="short">The United States of America</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Department of State, 2008</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Legislation">
                <head>Legislation</head>
                <p>Most permanent State Department records created prior to 1975 are with the
                    National Archives and Records Administration. The Freedom of Information Act
                    (FOIA) gives researchers the right to obtain access to all US Government
                    executive branch documents with nine statutory exceptions. State Department
                    records created after 1975 should be requested through FOIA. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Location">
                <head>Location</head>
                <p>National Archives at College Park 8601 Adelphi Road, College Park, MD 20740-6001
                </p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Procedures">
                <head>Procedures</head>
                <p>Researchers should take advantage of the on-line search engines to discover where
                    relevant records are located. Most State Department records are located at the
                    National Archives II at College Park, MD. However, the Presidential Libraries
                    are also important repositories of diplomatic documents, particularly those of
                    the National Security Council staff. A small number of diplomatic cables are
                    available on-line. Many frequently requested documents can be found on the State
                    Department’s Electronic Reading Room site. The State Department’s website also
                    gives guidance on making a FOIA request.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section" xml:id="Website">
                <head>Website</head>
                <p>
                    <ref target="http://www.archives.gov/">The National Records and Archives
                        Administration</ref>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <ref target="http://www.state.gov/m/a/ips/">The Department of State FOIA</ref>
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
